In this section then, we're going to
discuss Agile Ceremonies.
Now, a ceremony in Agile is really nothing
more than a meeting.
I mean, that's really all it is.
An Agile meeting, for some reason,
is known as a ceremony, right?
It is what it is, and it's just called a
ceremony.
It's just a meeting, though.
But there are several, there are a few
common types of meetings, though,
that you need to know.
So one of them, then, is this one called a
release planning, right?
Release planning, that's a agile ceremony.
many.
Okay.
Now, remember the general life cycle at
the beginning of a project, right,
an agile project.
So an agile project is known as a release,
right?
That is known as a release.
And the team facilitator, the product
owner, the agile team, you know,
they get together.
And in this case, they plan the work.
They plan the release, right?
They plan how many sprints we're going to
have, how many user
stories in each sprint.
The product owner is going to be creating
the product backlog as well.
That product backlog, remember,
is a prioritized list of user stories.
So you're collecting the user stories from
the customer, right?
User stories are the requirements,
collecting requirements from the customer,
right, which are in the agile world,
they're known as user stories.
So the agile team, team facilitator
product owner, right, work together with
the customer to get the list of user
stories.
but it's a product owner who represents
the customer.
It's a product owner who is going to
prioritize those user stories.
And then during release, all players,
right, the product owner, team
facilitator, agile team, now plan the
release, plan how many iterations,
how many sprints we need.
Now, Agile does have some planning,
right?
Even though Agile allows
for change, that doesn't
mean you're just making
it up as you go along.
No, you still need to plan.
Plans can change, but you still need to
plan.
So as a very simple example, let's say we
have 60 user stories.
This is just a very, very simple example.
We have 60 user stories, and we've got
this release is a six-month release.
So immediately we know then 10 user
stories per month.
If we're going to have two week sprint,
therefore five user stories per sprint.
Just a very simple example.
So that would be release planning.
Right.
And then also part of release planning as
well, the team is going to be doing some
high level relative estimating of these
user stories, right, which is a large user
story, which is a medium-sized user story
and so and so forth.
We're going to get into these relative
estimating in a separate video.
Now, another ceremony, another meeting,
another ceremony, is sprint planning,
right?
And, or it could be called iteration
planning, right?
Sprint or iteration.
And this is where the Agile
team now plans the work
for this current sprint
or the current iteration.
Right.
So they are going to take them,
they're going to work with the product
owner, right, to select
highest priority user stories,
right, these high priority
user stories, right?
And that's what they're going to implement
in this sprint.
And then during the sprint there,
they're going to create a sprint backlog.
So what is the highest priority user
stories for this sprint.
And then from those
user stories, they're going
to break those down
into individual activities.
What are all the tasks that need to be
done in order to fulfill the sprint?
Rather, in order to fulfill this user
story.
And then based on that now, they're going
to be doing some additional estimating,
right, and eventually estimating how long
each of these tasks are going to take.
And then they're going to be working on
those tasks, right?
They're going to be implementing them,
testing them, and so and so forth.
So, but that all needs to be planned
first, right?
So that's what sprint planning is.
Then you've got the daily stand-up
meeting.
Right, so on a daily basis during the
sprint, right, or during the two to
four-week iteration, right, you have the
daily stand-up meeting, that also known as
the daily scrum, right, if it's in a scrum
environment.
And it's hosted by the
team facilitator, and the team
is basically, all the team
is all going to be there.
It should only be 10 to 15 minutes,
no more than that.
It's just very timebox,
10 to 15 minutes, and
each team member is
addressing three items.
What did I accomplish yesterday?
What will I work on today?
And what impediments are there?
What impediments, blockers, issues,
what impediments are there?
And then the team
facilitator is going to discuss
those offline because
it's a team facilitator's job.
Remember, there's a servant leader.
It's their job.
part of their job is to remove impediments,
remove issues, remove obstacles.
Just as a side note, the basic difference
between an impediment and an obstacle,
an impediment is something that slows down
the work, right?
Whereas an obstacle or a blocker is
something that completely stops the work.
That's a high-level difference between an
impediment and a blocker.
So an impediment slows down the work.
So for example, if halfway through your
sprint, your senior executives are asking
your team members to run tons and tons of
reports.
Well, that's an impediment.
It's slowing down the work.
Right.
And so that's something that you,
you meaning the team facilitator now,
is going to have to address.
Whereas a blocker
would be, for example, we
can't move forward until we get a license.
Once we've gotten this license,
then we can start.
Until we get this license, there's
nothing.
we can do.
That's completely stopped the work or
completely prevented the work.
And in either case, it's a team
facilitator then that has to address that.
Other meetings, right, or other
ceremonies, you have this sprint review,
right, or the iteration review.
So at the end of each
sprint, at the end of each
iteration, right, you have
this sprint review meeting.
And this is really a meeting with the team
and the product owner.
And of course, the team facilitator as
well.
team is basically now delivering their
product to the product owner.
Whatever they've delivered or they're
deliverable, they're delivering it to the
product owner and the product owner is
either going to approve it or reject it.
Now other stakeholders can be there as
well, right, other customer stakeholders
but the primary stakeholder, the primary
customer is going to be the product owner.
Remember product owner
represents the customer and
they're either going
to approve it or reject it.
And then After the sprint
review, then you have a sprint
retrospective, right, or
an iteration retrospective.
And a retrospective is basically for the
benefit of the team.
So the team is going
to be there, the Agile
Team, right, as well
as the team facilitator.
The product owner can be there as well.
And it really is just a lessons learned
meeting.
Right, that's really all it is part of it.
Most of it is a lessons learned meeting,
right?
What went right, what went wrong,
and that kind of thing.
One of the principles of the Agile
Manifesto is Reflect, right?
So that's what the retrospective is.
And then also the close-out, or rather,
it also serves as the iteration close-out,
the sprint close-out, right?
Because now we're going to go into a new
sprint, so they can also be discussing,
you know, just high-level,
just high-level they can
discuss what we're going
to be doing in the next sprint.
All right, then other, just a couple of
other ceremonies.
I've got the backlog grooming and scrum of
scrums.
So backlog grooming just refers to
reprioritization of backlog items.
So remember in a scrum environment or
rather in an agile environment,
new user stories can be added at any time,
right, as things change.
So we've realized there's another
dependency or we've realized there's some
additional activities that need to be
done.
or there's a regulatory
requirement, or there's
a change in the external
business environment.
So now we need to add in some additional
user stories.
Everything needs to get reprioritized.
So that's what backlog grooming is.
Or estimates may need to be modified based
on some new information we've identified.
So again, that might end up reprioritizing
some of your backlog items.
So that's known as backlog grooming.
And then scrum of scrums, if you ever come
across this, and this is obviously
primarily for the scrum environment or the
scrum methodology.
Remember, in an agile world, agile teams
are generally small teams, teams of
developers, testers, designers,
business analysts with T-shaped skills.
They have these T-shaped skills.
And we're going to be discussing T-shaped
skills in a separate video.
But they're all small teams.
Now, what happens if it's a large project?
In which case, then, we're not going to
have a large team.
what we're going to do is we're going to
have several small teams.
However, we don't want these teams to be
working in silos either.
So we're going to have what's known as
scrum of scrum meetings, where a
representative from each team uses the
scrum master, is going to attend,
discuss progress and so and so and so
forth.
And that's really all a scrum of scrum is,
it's just a meeting with, you know,
it's like a team lead meeting,
if you like, or a manager's meeting.
So all the managers that go to one
meeting, the whole team doesn't go there.
It's just a team lead or the manager, the
team lead meeting,
the team leads go there.
In this case, then
Scrum of Scrum, it's just
all the scrum masters
that generally go there.
Now, it doesn't have to be the team
facilitator, scrum master.
It could be another representative,
right, but generally speaking.
But it has to be at least a
representative from each
team, attend one of these
scrum of scrum ceremonies.